<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tejbir (Tj) Wason</title>
    <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tejbir (Tj) Wason</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tejbirwason.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DOMContentLoaded vs window.onload What&#39;s the Difference</title>
      <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_domcontentloaded-vs-window.onload-whats-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_domcontentloaded-vs-window.onload-whats-the-difference/</guid>
      <description>When building web pages, it&amp;rsquo;s important to know when to execute JavaScript. Two crucial events, DOMContentLoaded and window.onload, can help you determine this. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the differences.
Timing DOMContentLoaded: Fires when the HTML document is fully parsed. The DOM is ready, but resources like images might not be loaded yet. window.onload: Fires when the entire page, including all resources (images, stylesheets, etc.), is fully loaded. Use Cases DOMContentLoaded: Ideal for running JavaScript as soon as the DOM is ready, without waiting for all resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incentive Structures in Venture Funds: LPs vs. GPs</title>
      <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_incentive-structures-in-venture-funds-lps-vs.-gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_incentive-structures-in-venture-funds-lps-vs.-gps/</guid>
      <description>Venture funds are primarily powered by two key participants: Limited Partners (LPs) and General Partners (GPs). Each has distinct roles and incentives.
Limited Partners (LPs) Role: Investors in the fund, providing capital for investments.
Incentives:
Capital Returns: Earn returns from portfolio exits and distributions. Preferred Return: Often, LPs have a &amp;ldquo;hurdle rate&amp;rdquo; ensuring they receive a minimum return before GPs take their profit share. General Partners (GPs) Role: Managers of the fund, making investment decisions and managing portfolio companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kouign-Amann</title>
      <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_kouign-amann/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_kouign-amann/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned about a pastry that&amp;rsquo;s giving croissants a run for their money: the kouign-amann (pronounced &amp;ldquo;queen a-mahn&amp;rdquo;). Hailing from Brittany, France, this buttery pastry dates back to the 1860s.
Legend has it that a baker in Douarnenez, faced with leftover bread dough, decided to incorporate butter and sugar and then baked it. The outcome was an unexpectedly delightful treat which would later gain fame not just in Brittany, but globally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prettier and Minified Code</title>
      <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_prettier-and-minified-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tejbirwason.com/posts/2023-08-11_prettier-and-minified-code/</guid>
      <description>Today, I learned that Prettier, the popular code formatter, can handle minified JavaScript code and try to format it into a readable form. However, there are some things to be aware of:
Performance Concerns: Prettifying large minified files (e.g., libraries) can be time-consuming. Accuracy: Minified code might not always format cleanly due to certain minification tricks. Original Structure: Prettified minified code won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily match the original code structure. Minification often renames variables and changes the code&amp;rsquo;s structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.tejbirwason.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.tejbirwason.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Tj.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
